<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PPMonth SYSTEM "../../../month.dtd">
<PPMonth>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<title>Mythology</title>
	<icon href="icon.png"/>
	<notes>Thanks to Portland regular Andrea Blumberg for writing all of this month's puzzles!  Like her stuff as much as we do?  Check out the amazing [Princess Bride puzzle set](http://www.puzzledpint.com/puzzles/may-2014/) she wrote for the May 2014 Puzzled Pint.</notes>
	<location>
		<puzzle>
			<title>Mnemosyne's Journey</title>
            <notes>Note: Do not print this puzzle!  One of these pictures is an animated GIF and the puzzle will be unsolvable if printed.</notes>
			<file href="http://www.puzzledpint.com/march_2015/"/>
			<hint>Mnemosyne has collected an object from each of the eight characters around her. Figure out which object belongs to which character.</hint>
			<hint>The objects in order belong to:

- Minotaur
- Golden Fleece
- Prometheus
- Pegasus
- Pandora
- Atlas
- Cyclops
- Medusa</hint>
			<hint>The number in the red circle indicates the index of the letter you need from each word.</hint>		
			<hint>The animated graphic sequentially adds one item from each picture, allowing us to create an order of eight myths:
                
- Minotaur
- Golden Fleece
- Prometheus
- Pegasus
- Pandora
- Atlas
- Cyclops
- Medusa

The animated graphic also gives a sequence of numbers, which can be indexed into the names:

- 1 - M
- 9 - E
- 4 - M
- 2 - E
- 3 - N
- 2 - T
- 5 - O
- 5 - S

The puzzle solution is MEMENTOS.</hint>
			<solution href="00-location-solution.txt" />
		</puzzle>
		<answerword>mementos</answerword>
	</location>
	
	<puzzle>
		<title>Proteus</title>
        <notes>Print double-sided.</notes>
		<file href="01-proteus-puzzle.pdf"/>
		<solution href="01-proteus-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>
	
	<puzzle>
		<title>Cassandra</title>
		<file href="02-cassandra-puzzle.pdf"/>
		<solution href="02-cassandra-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>
	
	<puzzle>
		<title>Arachne</title>
		<file href="03-arachne-puzzle.pdf"/>
		<solution href="03-arachne-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>
	
	<puzzle>
		<title>Icarus</title>
        <notes>Information about re-creating the original version of this puzzle, for Puzzle Party hosts ("encrypted as [ROT-13](http://rot13.com/)"):

Gur irefvba cbfgrq bayvar vf abg jung jnf ninvynoyr ng gur Znepu 2015 Chmmyrq Cvag rirag.  N zber pbzcyrk irefvba bs gur chmmyr jnf hfrq, juvpu vapyhqrq n fgrc gb ubyq gur fha nern bs gur cntr gb n synzr.  Jura urngrq, fcrpvny vax erirnyrq n erohf bs gur chmmyr fbyhgvba.

Vs lbh'q yvxr gb erperngr guvf irefvba, fgneg jvgu gur [bevtvany irefvba](04-icarus-puzzle_alt.pdf) bs gur chmmyr.  Gb znxr gur vaivfvoyr vax, zvk 1 grnfcbba bs onxvat fbqn jvgu 1 grnfcbba bs jngre.  Gura, hfvat n gbbgucvpx, jevgr "UBG JVATF" va gur fha.  Be, vs lbh'er srryvat negvfgvp, lbh pna qenj n [erohf vzntr](04-icarus-rebus.jpg).  Qenj yvtugyl fb gung gur yvarf qba'g vaqrag gur cncre.</notes>
		<file href="04-icarus-puzzle.pdf"/>
		<solution href="04-icarus-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>
	
	<puzzle>
		<title>Four Corners (meta puzzle)</title>
        <notes>Print double-sided.</notes>
		<file href="05-four_corners-puzzle.pdf"/>
		<solution href="05-four_corners-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>
	
	<answerSheet href="answersheet.pdf"/>
	<answerSheetSolution href="answersheet-solution.pdf"/>
</PPMonth>
