<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PPMonth SYSTEM "../../month.dtd">
<PPMonth>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<title>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</title>
	<notes>
	</notes>
	<location>
		<puzzle>
			<title>The Enchanted Forest</title>
			<file href="00-location-puzzle.pdf"/>
			<hint>This is a form of a common puzzle type called "Signpost" or "Arrow Path"

See [this page](http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/puzzles/js/signpost.html) for an example.</hint>
			<hint>It's helpful to number each step of your path from 1 (The starting square in the top left corner) to 16 (the cave entrance in the lower right corner)</hint>
			<hint href="00-location-hint3.png" />
			<hint>Beyond the "moors" is meant to clue morse code</hint>
            <hint>Bags of gold/coins on your path are dots, and keys are dashes.</hint>
            <hint>ITEMS COLLECTED

-- .- --. .. -.-.</hint>
			<hint>The solution is MAGIC</hint>
			<solution href="00-location-solution.pdf" />
		</puzzle>
		<answerword>magic</answerword>
	</location>

	<puzzle>
		<title>Fighter — Suiting Up</title>
		<file href="01-Fighter-puzzle.pdf"/>
        <hint>You have 9 types of armor you must wear, and 2 choices for each, but which of the two?</hint>
        <hint>Notice anything strange about those names?</hint>
        <hint>Each pair of names sounds like real English words that are opposites.</hint>
        <hint>PARTIAL ANSWER: Take the first word of each of these pairs: 

- Gorget - Agree over Disagree 
- Gauntlets - Good(eon) over Bad(mar)
- Helm - Virtue over Cin(dy)
- Shield - Correct(i) over Incorrect(sun)
- Greaves - Smart(en) over Dumb(a)
- Braces - Just(in) over Unfair
- Girdle - Zenith(um) over Nadir
- Boots - Pos(sy) over Neg(gritte)
- Breastplate - Yes over No(bby)</hint>
        <hint>Your total negative AC should be -24</hint>
        <hint>You'll want to wear each armor piece in order from head to toe (shield to boots).</hint>
        <hint>Do a ceasar shift of the first letters of each item's name (+2 is equivalent to -24)</hint>
		<solution href="01-Fighter-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>

	<puzzle>
		<title>Magic User — Memorizing Spells</title>
		<file href="02-MagicUser-puzzle.pdf"/>
        <hint>The given orientation of each scroll is a clue for how to fill in the grid</hint>
        <hint>You want to put each word into the grid so that the center of the word aligns with a reasonable description given by the intersection of the grid's labeled axis words. For example DISINTEGRATE is REMOVE OBJECT.</hint>
        <hint>You need to now again "combine two ideas" that you haven't used yet to finish the puzzle</hint>
        <hint>Add the row and column values for each grey square to get the right order in which to read their letters</hint>
		<solution href="02-MagicUser-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>

	<puzzle>
		<title>Cleric — Turning Around</title>
		<file href="03-Cleric-puzzle.pdf"/>
        <hint>Left to right, top to bottom: Skeleton Devourer Spectre

- Mummy Skeleton Spectre
- Zombie Spectre Devourer
- Zombie Vampire Skeleton</hint>
        <hint>You have answers, you need an index to extract letters. What piece of information haven't you used yet?</hint>
        <hint>Look at the size in grid squares of each of the lairs on the map use that to extract from the name of the monster.</hint>
		<solution href="03-Cleric-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>

	<puzzle>
		<title>Thief — Picking Locks</title>
		<file href="04-Thief-puzzle.pdf"/>
        <hint>Your code sheet will be very useful for this puzzle.</hint>
        <hint>You need a KEY in different encoded forms</hint>
        <hint>Top Left Lock: Hmm, coiled springs and cylindrical tumblers what code sheet column might apply?</hint>
        <hint>This is morse code. Just add the key.</hint>
        <hint>Literally add K-E-Y in morse code into the white space for the key</hint>
        <hint>Now read morse from bottom to top (as if the lock were turned right-way up)</hint>
        <hint>Top Right Lock: You have 3 sets of 5 boxes. What code sheet column could apply?</hint>
        <hint>This is binary. Just add the key.</hint>
        <hint>Literally add K-E-Y in binary code into the spaces</hint>
        <hint>Notice 5 bits stick out the top, and 5 stick out the bottom. you need 2 letters for the blanks.</hint>
        <hint>Bottom Left Lock: What code sheet column do those characters remind you of? You need a NEW code sheet!</hint>
        <hint>This is Pig Pen.</hint>
        <hint>Rotate the dials (in your head or cut them out) until you can spell K-E-Y in pigpen down from the top center</hint>
        <hint>Now read the 6 o'clock side of the lock in pigpen too.</hint>
        <hint>Bottom Right Lock: What code sheet column haven't you used yet? That EYE is a clue.</hint>
        <hint>This is Braille. Just add the key.</hint>
        <hint>Blacken the bumps on the box corresponding to the letters of K-E-Y in braille. Each 2x3 rectangle is a letter.</hint>
        <hint>Now read the circled letters left to right, top to bottom.</hint>
		<solution href="04-Thief-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>

	<puzzle>
		<title>You Slayed the Dragon! (meta puzzle)</title>
		<file href="05-YouSlayedTheDragon-puzzle.pdf"/>
        <hint>This is a deduction puzzle. Start with putting the line containing "last 10 damage needed to slay the dragon" in the last slot.</hint>
        <hint>The dragon's damage will be consistent based on which attack he uses. So his tail will always do 5 damage.</hint>
        <hint>As you can tell from the "20 damage kills you" line, his fire breath always must be avoided by using your cloak</hint>
        <hint>You'll want to heal when you're down to exactly 1 hit point.</hint>
        <hint>His jaws will do more damage than his claw</hint>
        <hint>Once you have the right choices, notice which item you used for each line.</hint>
        <hint>Apply the Initative value as an index on the puzzle answer corresponding to the item you used on each line</hint>
		<solution href="05-YouSlayedTheDragon-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>

	<puzzle>
		<title>Songs of the Bard (bonus puzzle)</title>
		<file href="06-SongsOfTheBard-puzzle.pdf"/>
        <hint>"Across" is meant to clue you to look for an acrostic</hint>
        <hint>Each song's lyrics spells an acrostic for a number and a Performer or Band's name (except Garb)</hint>
        <hint>Save the number for later indexing, all you need is the title and text to find a popular real song name</hint>
        <hint>"Colorful" is your second hint to choose the right song</hint>
        <hint>Each puzzle song title is reminiscent of the non-color words of the right title</hint>
        <hint>Each puzzle song text is reminiscent of some lyrics to the right son, which you can use to confirm.</hint>
        <hint>The Songs: 

- Red, Red Wine (UB40)
- Orange Crush (R.E.M.)
- Yellow Submarine (Beatles)
- Green River (Creedence Clearwater Revival)
- Blue Moon (The Marcels)
- Purple Rain (Prince)</hint>
        <hint>Now use the number to index into the song titles (NOTE: You didn't need to actually figure out Greensleeves as you knew it would start with G)</hint>
        <hint>Rainbow color order is the correct ordering of the letters</hint>
		<solution href="06-SongsOfTheBard-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>

	<puzzle>
		<title>Meta-Meta (bonus puzzle using all twelve 2016 themes)</title>
		<file href="07-MetaMeta-puzzle.pdf"/>
        <hint>You need to place the rectangles on the first page into the empty boxes on the second to answer the trivia questions.</hint>
        <hint>Each month's theme can act as a slight hint to the answer as it should be at least loosely related.</hint>
        <hint>The unused boxes are EV, LTHI, and RTHD</hint>
        <hint>Additional Hints:

1. Not real estate nor theft
2. The title is "Now Here's My Plan"
3. Christoper &amp; Josie
4. Lady Jane Grey was the 9-day queen
5. http://parksandrecreation.wikia.com/wiki/Congressman_Murray 
6. You burn the first part. The city has a Native American name.
7. Not things tyou pick up, nor is it shortsteel.
8. It's a shortcut through space and time, and Worf was one of these.
9. The first book in the series, when he was still a lieutenant, is called The Road to the Rim.
10. This year it's what Trump and Clinton awaits, and the 'exit' one of these will give early results.
11. He was the president between the Bushes
12. Elk are also known for the first part, and Eisenhower also promised the second part (Peace &amp; `____`)</hint>
        <hint>Trivia Answers:

1. Property, Stealing
2. A Book of Futilities
3. Walken, Bissett
4. Bradgate Park
5. Barkley, Robot
6. Calories, Milwaukee
7. Droppings, Longwood
8. Wormhole, Klingons
9. Grimes, Chandler
10. Election Day, Polls
11. Bill Clinton
12. Antlers, Prosperity</hint>
        <hint>Use the number in/under each box as an index into that box to know which letter to extract for the final answer</hint>
		<solution href="07-MetaMeta-solution.pdf"/>
	</puzzle>

	<allPuzzles href="allpuzzles.pdf"/>
	<answerSheet href="answersheet.pdf"/>
</PPMonth>